this video was made possible by Brilliant
这段视频是由Brilliant制作的
learn with Brilliant for twenty percent off by
以八折优惠与Brilliant一起学习
being one of the first two hundred to sign up
成为首批报名的200人之一
at Brilliant dot org slash wentover
在Brilliant dot org slash wentover
a single aircraft carrier is enough to markedly
一艘航空母舰就足以显著
change the level of a nation's military might
改变一个国家的军事实力水平
these ships are one of the strongest
这些船是最强大的
single assets a military can have
军队可以拥有的单一资产
in general  under international law
一般根据国际法
aircraft carriers can legally position
航空母舰可以合法定位
themselves up to fourteen miles or twenty
他们自己长达十四英里或二十英里
two kilometers from any country's coast
距离任何国家海岸两公里
clearly the strategic influence of being able
显然能够产生战略影响
to place a military airbase just miles from
在几英里外建立一个军事空军基地
any coast in the world is enormous
世界上任何海岸都是巨大的
especially given that eighty percent of the
尤其是考虑到百分之八十的
world's population lives within sixty miles or
世界人口居住在60英里或
a hundred kilometers from the ocean
离海洋一百公里
while plenty of military vessels are
虽然很多军舰
capable of launching helicopters
能够发射直升机
there are just nineteen aircraft carriers worldwide
全世界只有19艘航空母舰
currently in service capable of launching fixed wing
目前正在服役的能够发射固定翼
airplanes
飞机
China  Thailand  India  Russia and France each have one
中国、泰国、印度、俄罗斯和法国各有一个
Italy has two
意大利有两个
and the u s has the eleven largest in the world
美国有世界上最大的11个。
these largest carriers require over
这些最大的运营商需要超过
six thousand people to operate
六千人来操作
and often stay deployed for up to a year
并且经常部署长达一年
they are fully fledged cities at sea
它们是成熟的海上城市
mostmost advanced aircraft carriers like the
最先进的航空母舰，比如
French Navy's Charles de Gaulle are capable of
法国海军的戴高乐能够
launching an aircraft every thirty seconds
每三十秒发射一架飞机
that means that for a brief period
这意味着在很短的一段时间内
when launching aircraft at its maximum rate
当以最大速率发射飞机时
the aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle becomes
戴高乐号航空母舰成为
busier than Charles de Gaulle airport in Paris
比巴黎戴高乐机场还忙
to be able to achieve such a capability
能够达到这样的能力
on a moving ship is no easy feat
在移动的船上可不是件容易的事
while the operation of these vessels gives
而这些船只的运作
militaries an enormous strategic advantage
军事优势巨大
they also represent one of their
他们也代表他们的一个
greatest operational challenges
最大的运营挑战
an aircraft carrier's offensive weapon is its aircraft
航空母舰的进攻武器是它的飞机
on board carriers tend to only have a small
船上的承运人往往只有少量
number of defensive weapons such as surface
水面等防御武器数量
to air missiles and machine guns
到空中导弹和机关枪
but of course
但是当然
just like any powerful military asset
就像任何强大的军事资产一样
these carriers are big targets
这些航母是大目标
it is for this reason that carriers
正是出于这个原因，运营商
never travel alone while on deployment
部署期间切勿单独旅行
while the exact composition can
而确切的成分可以
change depending on the mission
视任务而定
the carrier strike groups American carriers
航母战斗群美国航母
travel with are typically made up of a guided
旅行通常由导游组成
missile cruiser equipped with tomahawk missiles
装备战斧导弹的导弹巡洋舰
two guided missile destroyers
两艘导弹驱逐舰
an attack submarine
攻击潜艇
and a supply ship
和一艘补给船
an aircraft carrier is the flagship of the strike group
航空母舰是打击群的旗舰
meaning that in its command area
这意味着在其指挥区
it not only has a bridge and an air traffic control center
它不仅有一座桥和一个空中交通管制中心
it also has a flag bridge where an
它也有一个旗帜桥
admiral commands the entire strike group
上将指挥整个突击队
each of the group's ships serve some
该组织的每艘船都服务于一些
combination of offensive and defensive roles
攻防结合
the only exception is the supply ship
唯一的例外是补给船
most aircraft carriers don't need regular refueling
大多数航空母舰不需要定期加油
all Eleven American carriers and the
所有11艘美国航空母舰和
French one are nuclear powered
法国的是核动力的
meaning they can sail an unlimited distance
意味着他们可以无限远航
for twenty five years without refueling
25年不加油
even conventionally powered aircraft carriers like the UK's
即使是像英国这样的传统动力航空母舰
HMS Queen Elizabeth can travel up to twelve thousand miles
伊丽莎白女王号战舰可以航行1万2千英里
or eighteen thousand kilometers without refueling
或者一万八千公里不加油
making the need for stops infrequent
使停止的需要不频繁
while an American or French carrier could hypothetically
而美国或法国航空公司可以假设
sail non stop for years or even decades what they can't
不停地航行几年甚至几十年
do is carry enough food which is always needed and
要做的就是携带足够的食物，这些食物总是需要的
aviation fuel which is needed for combat operations to
作战行动所需的航空燃料
stay at sea for more than a few weeks at a time
一次在海上呆几个星期以上
it would be inefficient and place the carriers
这将是低效的，并放置载体
in a position of vulnerability to have to
处于脆弱的境地
visit a port every few weeks to restock
每隔几周去一个港口补货
especially during combat operations
尤其是在作战行动中
so they don't
所以他们不会
they restock while at sea
他们在海上补货
the supply ships that move as part of the strike group
作为攻击群的一部分移动的补给船
will sail off to a nearby port to take on fuel  ammunition
将驶往附近港口装载燃料弹药
food and mail
食品和邮件
sail back to the strike group
回到攻击群
then match speed and maneuver alongside the carrier
然后配合航母的速度和机动
from there the two ships will shoot
两艘船将从那里射击
lines across to each other
相互交叉的线
these lines are used to pull hoses over to the carrier
这些管线是用来把软管拉到输送带上的
which are used to transfer aviation fuel
用于运输航空燃料
to transfer solid supplies
运送固体物资
there are two methods
有两种方法
the first is attaching pallets to dollies that
第一个是将托盘连接到推车上
wheel cargo over to the carrier like a zip line
把货物像拉链一样推到承运人那里
the second method which is considered simpler yet more
第二种方法被认为更简单
dangerous is using helicopters to pick up pallets from the
危险是使用直升机从
resupply ship and flying them over to the carrier
再补给船飞到航母上
these transfers bring both crucial supplies like
这些转移带来了重要的供应，比如
food and some less crucial items like mail
食物和一些不太重要的物品，如邮件
but this isn't the only way mail
但这不是唯一的方式邮件
arrives on American aircraft carriers
抵达美国航空母舰
each carrier actually has a mailing
每个承运人实际上都有一个邮寄
address just like any building in the us
地址就像美国的任何建筑一样
for example  this is the uss Gerald r Ford address
例如，这是Gerald r Ford号的地址
families of sailors can send mail to these addresses
水手家属可以向这些地址发送邮件
in the same way that they could to any other
就像他们可以对任何其他人一样
and in fact
而事实上
it costs the exact same as a
它的成本与
shipment to any other us address
发货到任何其他美国地址
even if the ship is on the other side of the world
即使船在世界的另一端
sailors can even order packages online to their ship
水手甚至可以在线订购包裹到他们的船上
expedited mail often makes it from an
加急邮件通常从
address in the us to a carrier sailing
在美国的地址到航行的承运人
somewhere around the world in just ten days
十天后在世界的某个地方
having this speed requires more frequent
拥有这种速度需要更频繁的
deliveries than those of the logistic ships
比物流船的交货
but conveniently
但很方便
carriers are airports at sea
承运人是海上机场
american carriers currently use a fleet
美国航母目前使用一支舰队
of c-2 greyhounds as cargo aircraft
C-2灰狗运输机
providing a high frequency
提供高频率
often daily connection between carriers and shore
承运人和岸上之间的日常联系
when cruising in the South China sea
在南海巡航时
for example
例如
as the uss Ronald Reagan did in November 2018
就像罗纳德·里根号在2018年11月所做的那样
mail might be sent to Singapore via conventional means
邮件可能会通过传统方式发送到新加坡
a C two greyhound would then fly
C 2灰狗会飞
from the ship to Singapore
从船上到新加坡
pick up the mail
拿起邮件
and fly back to the ship
飞回飞船
as carriers sail around the world
随着航母在世界各地航行
the pickup points of the c-2 greyhounds are
C-2灰狗的接送点是
continuously shifted to nearby friendly nations
不断转移到附近的友好国家
while mail is wonders for increasing crew morale
虽然邮件是提高船员士气的奇迹
that's actually the lowest priority
这实际上是最低优先级
cargo for the c-2 greyhounds
C-2灰狗的货物
the aircraft are integral for bringing on spare parts
飞机是运送备件不可或缺的一部分
for all the carriers aircraft and transporting vips
所有航母飞机和运输贵宾
press and other individuals to and from the carriers
往返承运人的新闻界和其他个人
the c two greyhound is about the same
c 2灰狗差不多
size as an embraer one forty five
尺寸为一四五
a civilian aircraft capable of carrying fifty people
能载五十人的民用飞机
so it's not tiny
所以它不小。
the longest aircraft carrier in the world
世界上最长的航空母舰
which also happens to be the newest
这也是最新的
is the uss Gerald r Ford
是杰拉尔德·r·福特号
but even she is only one thousand one hundred and six
但即使是她也只有一千一百零六
feet or three hundred and thirty seven meters long
三百三十七米长
with commercial airports a runway of five thousand feet
商业机场有五千英尺的跑道
or fifteen hundred meters like the one at London city
或者像伦敦那样1500米
airport in London is considered short while large
伦敦机场被认为是短而大
airports like London heathrow will have runways longer
像伦敦希思罗机场这样的机场将拥有更长的跑道
than ten thousand feet or three thousand meters
超过一万英尺或三千米
so how do c two greyhounds and other aircraft on
那么如何使用两只灰狗和其他飞机呢？
carriers deal with having runways of only one thousand
航空公司处理只有一千条跑道的问题
one hundred feet or three hundred and thirty meters long
一百英尺或三百三十米长
they don't  they take off with just three hundred and twenty
他们没有，他们只带着三百二十英镑离开了。
five feet or ninety nine meters of space
五英尺或九十九米的空间
all us and french carriers use a system of catapults to get
所有美国和法国航母都使用弹射器系统
aircraft up to takeoff speed within three to four seconds
飞机在三到四秒内达到起飞速度
this allows these carriers to launch a
这允许这些运营商推出一个
decently sized aircraft like the c-2
像c-2这样大小适中的飞机
greyhound with their relatively short decks
有着相对较短甲板的灰狗
other carriers like the Chinese and Indian ones Don't have
其他运营商，比如中国和印度的，没有
catapults so they can only launch lighter shorter range
弹射器，所以他们只能发射更轻的更短的射程
aircraft capable of taking off with a very short runway
能在极短跑道上起飞的飞机
both these two types of carriers have
这两种类型的运营商都有
arrestor wires that aircraft catch on landing
飞机着陆时接住的拦阻线
to decelerate with a short distance given
在给定的短距离内减速
every other aircraft carrier out there can only
其他的航空母舰只能
operate with aircraft capable of vertical landing
使用能够垂直着陆的飞机操作
what takes place on the flight deck is
飞行甲板上发生的是
carefully choreographed chaos
精心编排的混乱
on American carriers
在美国航空公司
everyone's job is easily
每个人的工作都很容易
identifiable by the color shirt they wear
可以通过他们穿的颜色衬衫来识别
yellow shirts deal with
黄衬衫处理
navigating aircraft around the deck
在甲板上驾驶飞机
blue shirts are assistants to yellow shirts driving tugs
蓝衬衫是黄衬衫驾驶拖船的助手
operating elevators
操作电梯
delivering messages  and more
传递消息等等
red shirts do all the handling and mounting of ammunition
红衫军负责处理和安装弹药
purple shirts manage aircraft fueling
紫色衬衫管理飞机加油
green shirts are worn by a few
绿色衬衫是少数人穿的
different groups including catapult crews
不同的团体，包括弹射队
maintenance personnel
维修人员
cargo handlers  and more
货物搬运工等
white shirts are also worn by a mix of
白衬衫也由混合穿着
personnel including those helping aircraft land
包括帮助飞机着陆的人员
working as medical personnel  and more
担任医务人员等等
and lastly brown shirts are worn by plane captains
最后，机长穿棕色衬衫
who are not those that fly the aircraft
谁不是那些驾驶飞机的人
they're individually in charge of overseeing all
他们单独负责监督所有
work for getting an aircraft ready for flight
使飞机准备好飞行
the flight deck is a dangerous place given its small size
飞行甲板是个危险的地方因为它太小了
it's so small that all the
它太小了，所有的
carriers aircraft can't fit on it
舰载机装不下
but of course just below the flight deck is the hangar
当然，飞行甲板下面就是机库
a large carrier can carry up to one hundred aircraft
一艘大型航母最多可搭载100架飞机
so massive elevators bring aircraft from the flight
巨大的升降机把飞机从飞机上拉下来
deck to the hangar for storage when not in use
不用时甲板到机库存放
about six thousand people work and
大约六千人工作
live aboard each American carrier
住在每艘美国航空母舰上
thirty two hundred of them have jobs
其中3200人有工作
related to running the ship itself
与管理船本身有关
that includes everything from working in the engine room
这包括从在机舱工作的一切
maintaining the nuclear reactor
维护核反应堆
cleaning the decks
清理甲板
to actually working up in the bridge commanding the ship
在舰桥上指挥飞船
many of these jobs are below deck
这些工作中有许多是不正当的
and since all the above deck space
由于上面所有的甲板空间
is used for flight operations
用于飞行操作
many onboard can go weeks without seeing sunlight
许多船上的人可以连续几周看不到阳光
twenty five hundred other personnel are
其他两千五百名人员是
part of the carrier's air wing
航母机翼的一部分
if this was an airbase on land
如果这是陆地上的空军基地
these would be everyone working there
这些是在那里工作的每个人
including air traffic controllers
包括空中交通管制员
aircraft mechanics  fuelers
飞机机械师加油机
pilots and more
飞行员和更多
the few hundred remaining
剩下的几百个
personnel work assorted other jobs
人事工作分类其他工作
in terms of personal space enlisted personnel
在个人空间方面入伍人员
the vast majority of those on board
船上的绝大多数人
only get a single bunk in a room with
只能在一个房间里得到一个单人床
sometimes more than a hundred others
有时超过一百个
higher ranked individuals though
虽然排名较高的个人
of course have more spacious accommodations
当然有更宽敞的住宿
as long term homes for thousands of people
作为成千上万人的长期住所
these ships also have a few small luxuries like stores
这些船也有一些小奢侈品，如商店
gyms  barber shops
健身房理发店
lounges and more
休息室等
but space is at a premium when six thousand
但是空间是非常宝贵的，当六千
people are packed into one floating hotel
人们挤在一个浮动酒店里
and the mission is Paramount
任务是派拉蒙
since their heyday in World War II
从他们在二战的全盛时期开始
some have started to question the place
有些人开始质疑这个地方
aircraft carriers have in modern warfare
航空母舰在现代战争中
every operating country aside from the us tend to at
除了美国，每个运营国家都倾向于
any given moment have their ships either in combat
任何时候他们的船要么在战斗中
in training  or at home
在训练中还是在家里
the us tends to use its carriers for a fourth function
美国倾向于将其运营商用于第四个功能
power projection
功率投射
at any given moment
在任何给定的时刻
there is almost certainly an American
几乎可以肯定有一个美国人
carrier cruising somewhere in the world  in fact
航母实际上在世界的某个地方巡航
January twenty seventeen was the first time
1月27日是第一次
since World War II that there was not an
自二战以来，没有一个
American aircraft carrier on deployment
部署中的美国航空母舰
even if there wasn't an aircraft carrier on deployment
即使部署的不是航空母舰
they're fast
他们很快
they have a top speed of thirty five
他们的最高速度是35英里
miles or fifty six kilometers per hour
每小时五十六公里
meaning that a Norfolk Virginia based carrier
这意味着一家位于弗吉尼亚州诺福克的航空公司
could get to the Middle East in just a week
可以在一周内到达中东
in the Pacific
在太平洋
the us has an even greater advantage
美国的优势更大
since it has the uss Ronald Reagan based in Yokosuka Japan
因为罗纳德·里根号航空母舰驻扎在日本横须贺
from where it could reach the shores of North Korea
从那里它可以到达朝鲜海岸
for example in just twenty nine hours
例如在短短二十九小时内
American carriers spend plenty of time just
美国航空公司花了很多时间
cruising around the world's oceans
在世界海洋中巡航
reminding other countries of the u s's military power
提醒其他国家美国的军事力量
for example
例如
the u s s Ronald Reagan returned from a four
美国罗纳德·里根号从四号回来
month deployment from August to December 2018
2018年8月至12月的月部署
during which it saw zero combat
在此期间没有战斗
they spent much of the time
他们花了很多时间
cruising around the South China sea
在南中国海巡航
an area in which China is
中国所在的地区
attempting to assert military control
企图实施军事控制
much to the us's displeasure
令美国非常不满
elsewhere in Asia  American carriers also
在亚洲其他地方，美国航空公司也
regularly make visits to the Korean peninsula
定期访问朝鲜半岛
to remind North Korea of their presence
提醒朝鲜他们的存在
this reached a peak in November twenty seventeen
这在1917年11月达到了顶峰
as tensions with North Korea reached a peak when
随着与朝鲜的紧张局势达到顶峰
three American carriers loomed near Korean shores
三艘美国航母逼近韩国海岸
with their enormous power though
尽管他们拥有巨大的力量
aircraft carriers represent an enormous target
航空母舰是一个巨大的目标
especially in the era of stealthy
尤其是在隐身时代
drones and precise missiles
无人机和精确导弹
the sinking of a single us aircraft carrier could result in
一艘美国航空母舰的沉没可能导致
more American military deaths than the entire Iraq war
美军死亡人数比整个伊拉克战争还多
in addition to the loss of tens of
除了损失几十
billions of dollars in military assets
数十亿美元的军事资产
while no aircraft carrier of any nation
虽然没有任何国家的航空母舰
has been sunk since World War II
自二战以来一直沉没
it's potentially more possible than one would think
这可能比人们想象的更有可能
u s carriers regularly participate in war games
美国航母定期参加战争游戏
where combat conditions are simulated with allies
在那里与盟友一起模拟战斗条件
there have been two concerning incidents in two thousand
2000年发生了两起令人担忧的事件
five and two thousand fifteen where Swedish and French
五千二百一十五瑞典语和法语
submarines respectively have won the games against u s
潜艇分别赢得了对美国的比赛
carriers
承运人
what this means is that the two country submarines
这意味着两国潜艇
approached close enough to the carriers where they could
尽可能靠近航母
have  if they were an enemy in real combat
如果他们在真正的战斗中是敌人
launch torpedoes and potentially sink the carriers
发射鱼雷并可能击沉航母
this in essence proves that aircraft carriers with all
这实质上证明了航空母舰与所有
their defense are not as unsinkable as some may say
他们的防御并不像有些人说的那样坚不可摧
meanwhile  the us has already received the first
与此同时，美国已经收到了第一个
of ten in a new class of carriers
十艘新航母
while China  India and the uk each
而中国、印度和英国各
have carriers under construction  so
有承运人在建，所以
despite their possible obsolescence
尽管它们可能已经过时
we can be sure that the aircraft carrier won't be
我们可以肯定航空母舰不会
leaving the world's oceans any time soon
很快就会离开地球的海洋
i have a logic question for you
我有一个逻辑问题要问你
00:00 suppose there are two doors
00:00假设有两扇门
and the first has a sign on it saying
第一个上面有一个标志，上面写着
if this door is safe
如果这扇门是安全的
the other door is deadly
另一扇门是致命的
if that sign is false
如果那个标志是假的
what do you know about the doors
你对门了解多少？
which are deadly and which are safe
哪些是致命的哪些是安全的
take a moment to think about it
花点时间考虑一下
and if you figure out the answer
如果你想出了答案
leave it in the comments
把它留在评论里
this is a question from Brilliant org's logic quiz
这是Brilliant组织逻辑测验中的一个问题
which teaches you analytical
它教你分析
skills through logical puzzles
逻辑谜题技巧
that's just one of many superbly
这只是众多卓越之一
designed courses on Brilliant
关于Brilliant的设计课程
through which you can learn about dozens
通过它你可以了解大约几十个
of topics including group theory
包括群论在内的主题
multivariable calculus  statistics
多变量微积分统计
number theory
数论
machine learning  and more
机器学习等等
they're experts in teaching scary complicated subjects in
他们是教授恐怖复杂学科的专家
a way in which you can actually understand them by
一种你可以真正理解它们的方式
breaking them down into their fundamental principles
把它们分解成基本原则
get started learning with Brilliant for free at Brilliant
开始在Brilliant免费学习Brilliant
org slash wendover
org斜杠wendver
and then the first two hundred that go to that link will
然后进入该链接的前200个将
get twenty percent off their annual premium subscription
从他们的年度保费订阅中获得20%的折扣